# SHAUN STICKA

BROOKLYN PARK, MN 55445 (617) 386-6767 | SHAUN.STICKA@OUTLOOK.COM

LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SHAUNSTICKA **GITHUB:** GITHUB.COM/MNSHAUN24

PROFILE: MNSHAUN24.GITHUB.IO/SHAUN-PROFILE-FIRST/

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with an extensive background in education and curriculum development. Graduate of the University of Minnesota Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp. Hands on experience in both front and back-end design. Known for exceptional written and verbal communication skills, presenting complex topics to a variety of audiences, and working collaboratively across teams in an organization. Passion for problem solving and constant self-growth.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, MERN, MySQL, NoSQL, IndexedDB, Sequelize

Applications: AJAX, OOP, PWA, Webpack, MVC, API

#### **PROJECTS**

Beyond the Peak | https://github.com/glanctot/beyond-the-peak | https://pacific-journey-17528.herokuapp.com/

Summary: Beyond the Peak is a random drink generator that gives users the freedom to choose the level of randomness they would like it to generate. It also includes the ability to post and comment on drinks to share experiences.

Responsibilities: Project lead of a team of 3, project folder and code structure and layout, JavaScript functionality, assist with back-end routes

Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, JS, CSS, API, MySQL, Sequelize, JawsDB, Heroku, GitHub

Just Tech It I https://github.com/mnshaun24/just-tech-it I https://git.heroku.com/hidden-brushlands-94802.git

Summary: Just Tech It is a tech blog that uses MySQL as a database to store users, comments, and replies. The front-end is made with HTML and CSS.

Responsibilities: Build a tech blog from the ground up. Use MySQL and employ MVC structure to follow industry best practices.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JS, MySQL, SQL, JawsDB, Heroku, GitHub

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Content Developer**

January 2020 - Current Bloomington, MN

PearsonVUE

- Used PearsonVUE proprietary tools to develop and perform validation checks on upwards of 15 exam
- Prepared and facilitated multi-day workshops with clients and SMEs for exam creation
- Worked closely with other departments through an approximate 3-month cycle from exam creation to deployment
- Performed daily checks and proofs to ensure impeccable standards of delivering highly effective and ethical content

**Latin Teacher** October 2018 – June 2019

Thales Academy Apex. NC

Delivered highly effective learning content to approximately 210 students both in-person and virtual

- Created assessments for all students using collected data and input from department head
- Collaborated routinely with department head to assess learning solutions and modify as necessary
- Built student capabilities and motivated students, increasing test scores by 20 points from October to Mav
- Worked with the English and Math departments to ensure consistent student expectations via the school's LiveSchool tracker app

**Latin Teacher** August 2017 – September 2018 Lexinaton, SC

Lexinaton School District One

Led eleven classes both in-person and through virtual learning

- Created all assessments for in-person students and modified existing assessments for virtual students
- Developed and coordinated the implementation of a new virtual curriculum
- Worked with the intervention department to assist in their job providing remedial options to at-risk students
- Collaborated regularly with all the Latin teachers across the district to normalize grading and evaluation standards

**Writing Consultant** 

September 2015 - May 2017

Waltham, MA

Brandeis University

- Assisted undergraduate and graduate students in the writing process
- Developed students' grammar and writing clarity capabilities
- Assisted English Language Learner students in developing their English writing skills

**Latin Teacher Assistant** 

January 2016 - May 2016

Brandeis University

Waltham, MA

- Coordinated with the class professor to establish grading criteria for tests and classroom pace
- Graded and assessed undergraduate tests, providing constructive feedback

**Assistant Language Teacher, Matsumoto Elementary School** AtoZ Corporation

April 2011 – August 2015 Nagano Prefecture, Japan

- Designed English curriculum and learning approaches for 500 K-6 students
- Grew the English program from 6 classes a week to approximately 18 classes per week
- Built lesson plans in Japanese and worked with every teacher in the school to create rewarding content
- Coached students to a first-place finish in the prefectural speech contest
- Aided the special ed department and taught a small class of special needs students once per week

**AVID Program Assistant Teacher** 

Sept 2010 - March 2011

Wayzata High School

Wavzata. MN

- Taught AVID seminars in conjunction with English, Math, Social Studies, and Science teachers
- Instructed kids on essential concepts like source evaluation and problem solving

Assistant Language Teacher, Takamatsu Junior High School

July 2009 - August 2010 Kagawa Prefecture, Japan

Japanese Exchange and Teaching (JET) Program

- Selected by Japanese Ministry of Education and Ministry of Foreign Affairs to help promote foreign language education and grassroots internationalization in Japan
- Collaborated with Japanese teachers of English to develop and implement engaging and communicative English lessons for 450 elementary and middle school students
- Evaluated student performance through oral and written assessments

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bootcamp Certificate**

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

## **Master of Arts, Classical Studies**

Brandeis University, Waltham, MA

## **Bachelor of Arts, History**

Bachelor of Arts, Business Management; Minor: Latin

University of St. Thomas, St. Paul, MN

### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- 2019 Bi-Annual Professional Development
- 2018 Weekly Professional Development
- 2018 Lexington One World Language Professional Development
- 2018 PACE Program Training
- 2017 Lexington One World Language Professional Development
- 2014 English Language Learners Conference
- 2013 Foreign Language Teachers Conference
- 2012 Foreign Language Teachers Conference

## OVERSEAS STUDY AND COMMUNITY SERVICE

- 2016 Tel Dor Archaeological Excavation Volunteer; Haifa, Israel (July August)
- 2008 Orphanage construction service trip volunteer; Playa del Carmen, Mexico (January)
- 2007 Archaeology and History in Rome J-Term class; Rome (January)